The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: [INAUDIBLE] audio.
教授：[音频不清晰]。
We're going to have a series of lectures on shortest paths.
我们将在最短路径上进行一系列讲座。
And one of the big differences between this module
而这个模块之间的最大区别之一
and the previous one, at least from a mathematical standpoint,
至少从数学的角度来看，
is that we're going to be looking
是我们要去寻找
at graphs that have weights on their edges.
在边缘具有权重的图形上。
So when Eric talked about depth first search and breadth
因此，当埃里克（Eric）谈论深度优先搜索和广度时
first search in the last couple of lectures,
在最后两节课中首次搜索，
we had directed graphs and undirected graphs.
我们有向图和无向图。
But we didn't really have attributes on the edges.
但是，我们实际上并没有边缘属性。
In particular, you have a much richer class
特别是您的班级要丰富得多
of problems and applications if you
问题和应用程序，如果您
allow for weights on graph edges.
允许在图形边缘上加权。
And these weights can be integers.
这些权重可以是整数。
They could be real numbers, irrationals.
它们可能是实数，是非理性的。
They could be negative, what have you.
他们可能是负面的，你有什么。
And for different classes of graphs
对于不同类别的图
and different restrictions on weights,
以及不同的重量限制
there's really a set of shortest path algorithms,
确实有一组最短路径算法，
that we'll look at in the next few lectures, which
我们将在接下来的几节课中介绍
are kind of optimized for a particular application.
针对特定应用进行了优化。
So we won't do specific algorithms today.
因此，我们今天不做特定的算法。
But we'll set up the problem.
但是，我们将解决问题。
We'll talk about the general approach
我们将讨论一般方法
that most shortest path algorithms take
最短路径算法需要的
to solve a particular instance of a problem.
解决特定的问题实例。
And then we'll close with talking
然后，我们将结束交谈
about a particular property that's pretty important.
关于非常重要的特定财产。
That's called the optimum or optimal substructure property.
这称为最佳或最佳子结构属性。
That is a technique that most shortest path algorithms,
这是最短路径算法中的一项技术，
or actually all shortest path algorithms
或实际上所有最短路径算法
use to get efficient complexity.
用于获得有效的复杂性。
So asymptotic complexity is important, obviously.
因此，渐近复杂度很重要。
And we're always looking for the best algorithm with the best
而且我们一直在寻找具有最佳性能的最佳算法
asymptotic complexity.
渐进复杂度。
And optimal substructure is a hammer
最佳的子结构是一把锤子
that we're going to use to get that.
我们将用来获得它。
So the canonical motivation, of course, for shortest paths
因此，当然，最短路径的规范动机
is-- now, if you want to steal, or I
现在-如果您想偷东西，或者我
guess borrow, a cannon from Caltech
猜猜借来，来自加州理工学院的一门大炮
and bring it over to MIT, then you
交给麻省理工学院，然后你
want the fastest way of getting here with your illegal goods.
希望以最快的方式带走您的非法物品。
And you want to find the shortest way or the fastest
而您想找到最短的方法或最快的方法
way of getting from one location to another.
从一个位置到达另一位置的方法。
So Google Maps go from point A to point
因此，Google Maps从A点移到了
B. That's a classic application of the shortest path problem.
B.这是最短路径问题的经典应用。
In this case, you could imagine that distance
在这种情况下，您可以想象该距离
would be something that would be a very simple metric that you
将会是一个非常简单的指标
could use for the weights on the edges.
可用于边缘的权重。
So for this entire module, we're going
因此，对于整个模块，我们将
to be looking at a graph G V, E, W.
看图GV，E，W
And you know what V and E are.
而且您知道V和E是什么。
They're the vertices and the edges.
它们是顶点和边缘。
And W is a weight function that maps edges to weights.
W是将边缘映射到权重的权重函数。
And so we're adding that in here.
因此，我们将其添加到此处。
And so W would be E to R. So the set of real numbers.
因此W将是E到R。因此是实数集。
We're going to be looking at two different algorithms
我们将要研究两种不同的算法
in subsequent lectures.
在随后的讲座中。
And you'll implement one of them in your problem set.
您将在问题集中实施其中之一。
The simpler algorithm, which we'll look at first,
首先我们来看一下更简单的算法，
is called Dijkstra, after Edsger Dijkstra, who
以Edsger Dijkstra的名字命名为Dijkstra，
did some similar work in concurrent programming,
在并发编程中做了一些类似的工作，
won the Turing Award.
荣获图灵奖。
But on the side invented this cool algorithm--
但是在一边发明了这个很酷的算法
or at least gets credit for it-- called Dijkstra's algorithm
或至少得到赞誉-称为Dijkstra算法
that assumes non-negative weight edges.
假定非负权重边。
So I should really say non-negative.
所以我真的应该说非负面的。
So read that as non-negative.
因此，将其视为非负数。
And that has a complexity of order V log V plus E.
复杂度为V log V加上E。
All right.
好吧。
So this is practically linear time.
因此，这实际上是线性时间。
And typically, you're going to be dominated in many cases
通常，在许多情况下，您将被统治
by E. In general, if you talk about a simple graph, what's
通常，如果您谈论一个简单的图，那是什么
the asymptotic relationship between E and V?
E和V之间的渐近关系？
Can you relate E to V?
你能把E和V联系起来吗？
Can you give me a bound?
你能给我束缚吗？
AUDIENCE: V squared.
听众：V平方。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
V squared, thanks.
V平方，谢谢。
That's good.
那很好。
So you can think of E as being order V square.
因此，您可以将E视为V阶。
And you can certainly have-- that's worth recursion.
而且您当然可以拥有-值得递归。
So now, you can kind of imagine a complete graph.
所以现在，您可以想象一个完整的图形。
And a complete graph is something
完整的图形是
that has an edge between each pair of vertices.
在每对顶点之间都有一条边。
And that's where you'll get E being k w squared.
这就是E被平方平方的地方。
So when you say simple graph, you're
因此，当您说简单图形时，
saying you have at most one edge between any pair of vertices.
说您在任何一对顶点之间最多有一个边。
A multigraph is something that could
多重图形可以
have multiple edges between pairs of vertices.
在成对的顶点之间有多个边。
We won't really be talking about multigraphs
我们真的不会谈论多图
in this sequence of lectures.
在这一系列的讲座中。
But something to think about or keep in the back of your mind
但是有些事情需要考虑或留在脑海中
as we go through these algorithms.
当我们经历这些算法时。
And so the dominating factor here, and in many cases really,
所以这里是主要因素，在很多情况下，
is E. And Dijkstra is a nice algorithm, because it's
是E。Dijkstra是一个很好的算法，因为它是
linear in the number of edges.
边数线性。
So that's Dijkstra.
那就是Dijkstra。
And that's the first of the algorithms
这是第一个算法
that we'll look at next time.
下次再看。
But we'll see the general structure of Dijkstra today.
但是，今天我们将看到Dijkstra的一般结构。
And then there's the Bellman-Ford algorithm
然后是Bellman-Ford算法
that works on positive and negative edges, weight edges.
适用于正负边缘，权重边缘。
And this has a complexity order V E.
这具有复杂度阶V E。
So you could imagine a particular implementation
所以你可以想象一个特定的实现
of Bellman-Ford running in order V cubed time.
Bellman-Ford的运行顺序为V的立方时间。
Because E could be V square.
因为E可以是V平方。
And you've got this additional E factor.
而且您还有其他E因子。
So it's order V cubed versus order V log V.
因此，这是订单V的立方与订单V的对数V。
So when you have a chance, use Dijkstra.
因此，如果有机会，请使用Dijkstra。
When you're stuck, you'd want to do Bellman-Ford,
当您陷入困境时，您想要做Bellman-Ford，
because you have these negative weight edges.
因为您有这些负重边缘。
And one of the challenges in negative weight edges,
负边缘带来的挑战之一是
and I'll say a little bit more as we go along,
我们继续讲的话，
is that you end up having to have
是你最终不得不
to find cycles that are of a negative weight,
寻找负重量的自行车，
because they kind of throw off your shortest path algorithm
因为它们有点像您的最短路径算法
if you were just assuming that shortest path lengths are only
如果您只是假设最短路径长度仅
going to decrease.
会减少。
But when you have negative weights, you might take a step
但是当您的负体重不定时，您可以采取一些措施
and the overall weight might decrease.
并且总重量可能会减少。
So it's kind of a longer path in terms of the number of edges.
因此，就边缘数量而言，这是一条较长的路径。
But the weight is smaller.
但是重量更小。
And that kind of makes the algorithm more complicated.
这样会使算法更加复杂。
And it has to do more work.
它必须做更多的工作。
So that's really why there's a difference between these two
所以这就是为什么这两者之间会有区别的原因
complexities.
复杂性。
And I guarantee you, you'll understand this much better
我向您保证，您会更好地理解这一点
after we're done with the lectures on Dijkstra
在完成关于迪克斯特拉的讲座之后
and the lectures on Bellman-Ford.
以及关于贝尔曼福特的讲座。
So that's the set up for the problem.
这就是解决问题的方法。
That's what we're going to be looking at.
这就是我们要研究的内容。
Let's look at a couple more definitions
让我们再看几个定义
beyond what I have here with respect to just the notation.
超出了我在此处仅涉及的符号。
And you can think of path p as a sequence of vertices-- V0, V1,
您可以将路径p视为一个顶点序列-V0，V1，
et cetera, to Vk.
等，到Vk。
And this is the path if Vi, Vi plus 1
这是Vi，Vi加1时的路径
belongs to E for 0 less than or equal to i less than
属于E且0小于或等于i小于
or equal to k.
或等于k。
So a path is a sequence of edges.
因此，路径是一系列边沿。
And each of those edges has to be in the graph,
每个边都必须在图中
has to be in the set of edges E.
必须在边E的集合中。
And W of p, which is the weight of the path,
而W，即路径的权重，
we know that by the weight of edges, those are easy.
我们知道，通过边缘的重量，这些都很容易。
They're given by the W function.
它们由W函数给出。
The weight of the path is simply the summation
路径的权重只是总和
of the weights of the edges.
边缘的权重。
All right.
好吧。
So fairly obvious definitions.
如此明显的定义。
But obviously, we have to get these right in order
但是显然，我们必须正确地处理这些问题
to actually solve the problem correctly.
真正正确地解决问题。
And the shortest path problem is, as you can imagine,
如您所想，最短路径问题是
something that tries to find a path p that has minimum weight.
试图找到具有最小权重的路径p的东西。
So in general, you have some set up for the problem.
因此，总的来说，您已经为该问题做了一些准备。
But it comes down to find p with--
但是归结为找到-
And there are many, many possible paths.
并且有很多很多可能的途径。
You have to understand that there are potentially
您必须了解潜在的
an exponential number of paths in the graphs
图中路径的指数数量
that we would consider.
我们会考虑的。
And here's a real simple example where
这是一个真正简单的例子，
you would have an exponential number of paths.
您将拥有指数级的路径。
And we'll come back to this example later in the lecture.
我们将在稍后的演讲中回到这个例子。
But let's assume that all the directions go this way.
但让我们假设所有方向都是这样。
And it's a directed graph.
这是有向图。
Well, you could have the path that goes all the way here.
好吧，您可能会一直走到这里。
But you could have the path that goes on top
但您可能会走上一条路
and all the way this way.
一直这样。
You have basically two choices on getting to this vertex.
到达该顶点基本上有两种选择。
Then you've got, given the two ways
然后，有两种方法
you have of getting to this vertex.
你必须要达到这个顶点。
You've got four ways of getting here.
您有四种到达这里的方式。
And then, you have eight ways of getting there.
然后，您有八种到达那里的方法。
So on and so forth.
等等等等。
So there's an exponential number of paths potentially.
因此，潜在的路径数量呈指数级增长。
The other thing that's interesting here,
另一个有趣的地方是
which is important in terms of this complexity
就这种复杂性而言，这很重要
is, what's interesting about what you see here
是，你在这里看到的有趣的是
with respect to the complexity and what you see here.
关于复杂性以及您在这里看到的内容。
Anybody want to point that out?
有人要指出这一点吗？
So I have this complexity here and order VE out there.
所以我这里很复杂，在那里订购VE。
What's an interesting observation
有什么有趣的发现
if you look at this board here and the two complexities?
如果您在这里查看此板以及两个复杂性？
Anybody?
有人吗
Yeah, back there.
是的，回到那里。
AUDIENCE: It's not a function of weight.
听众：这不是体重的函数。
PROFESSOR: It's not a function of weight.
教授：这不是体重的函数。
Great.
大。
That's definitely worth recursion.
绝对值得递归。
And I'll let you throw this one.
我让你扔这个。
All the way back there, all right?
一路回到那里，好吗？
Right.
对。
All right, good.
好，好
Good, good.
好好。
That was good.
那很好。
That was better than what I could do.
那比我能做的更好。
No, not really.
不，不是。
But I would've been right in his hands right there.
但是我会一直在他的手中。
Anyway, so that's a great observation, actually.
无论如何，实际上这是一个很好的观察。
And I should have pointed it out right up front.
我应该事先指出这一点。
But I'm glad I got it out of you.
但是我很高兴我从你那得到了。
W doesn't exist in the complexity.
W不存在复杂性。
This is pretty important.
这很重要。
W could be a large number.
W可能很大。
I mean, it could be 2 raised to 64.
我的意思是，可以将2提高到64。
The fact is that there's only E square different values
事实是，只有E平方不同的值
possible for a weight, right.
可能的重量吧。
I mean, roughly speaking.
我的意思是，粗略地说。
If you have a complete graph, it's a simple graph,
如果您有完整的图形，那是一个简单的图形，
there's order E square possible weights.
有E阶可能的权重。
But the range of the weights could be exponential.
但是权重的范围可能是指数的。
I could have an edge weight of 0.0001
我的边缘权重为0.0001
and a different edge weight of 10 raised to 98.
然后将另一种边缘权重10提高到98。
There's nothing that's stopping me
没有什么可以阻止我
from doing that or putting a specification like that.
避免这样做或提出类似的规范。
But the nice thing about Dijkstra, and Bellman-Ford,
但是关于Dijkstra和Bellman-Ford的好处是，
and virtually all of the algorithms
几乎所有的算法
that are useful in practice is that they
在实践中有用的是
don't depend on the dynamic range of the weights.
不取决于权重的动态范围。
And so keep that in mind as you think
因此，请记住您的想法
of shortest path algorithms.
最短路径算法。
And we'll talk a little bit about this in section tomorrow,
明天我们将在本节中对此进行一些讨论，
or the TAs will, as to why breadth first search and depth
还是TA会问，为什么要进行广度优先搜索和深度
first search aren't directly applicable to the shortest path
首次搜索不适用于最短路径
problem.
问题。
And the hint really is the dynamic range of the weights.
提示实际上是权重的动态范围。
So keep that in mind.
所以记住这一点。
So a couple things why this is an interesting algorithm,
所以有几件事为什么这是一个有趣的算法，
or interesting problem to solve, and harder than the problems
或有趣的问题要解决，比问题更难
we've looked at so far like sorting and search,
到目前为止，我们一直在进行排序和搜索，
is that you have an exponential number of paths.
就是您的路径数是指数的。
And then the dynamic range of the weights
然后权重的动态范围
can be very, very large.
可以非常非常大。
And it's not linear by any means.
而且它绝不是线性的。
All right.
好吧。
So these algorithms are going to have to have some smarts.
因此，这些算法将必须具有一些智能。
And the optimal substructure property
以及最佳的子结构属性
that we'll look at towards the end of today's lecture
我们将在今天的演讲快结束时看一下
will give you a sense of how these algorithms actually
让您了解这些算法的实际效果
work in basically linear time.
在基本上线性的时间内工作。
Or VE, you could think of that as being
或VE，您可能会认为这是
cubic time in terms of the vertices.
以顶点表示的立方时间。
So keep that in mind.
所以记住这一点。
Let's talk a little bit more about weighted graphs.
让我们再谈谈加权图。
I want a little bit more notation.
我想要更多的符号。
And what I have is V0 using path p to Vk.
我拥有的是使用路径p到Vk的V0。
So I'm going to write that to say that there's
所以我要写的是说
a particular path of V0 to Vk.
V0到Vk的特定路径。
Sometimes I'm searching for the path p with a minimum weight.
有时我正在寻找最小重量的路径p。
And that's how I'm going to represent that.
这就是我要代表的方式。
V0, which is a single vertex path,
V0，这是一个单一的顶点路径，
is the path from V0 to V0.
是从V0到V0的路径。
So it's really a 0 length path.
因此，这实际上是长度为0的路径。
And it has weight 0.
权重为0。
So that's one condition.
这是一个条件。
The other condition that we need to look at,
我们需要考虑的另一个条件是
which is the other case, is what if there isn't a path?
否则，如果没有路径怎么办？
So I want to put those two things together,
所以我想把这两件事放在一起，
the two extremes, and of course all of the cases
这两个极端，当然，所有情况
in between, in this definition of the shortest pathway.
在这两者之间，在最短路径的定义中。
And so I'm going to talk about the shortest path
因此，我将讨论最短的路径
value of the weight of the shortest path between u and v
u和v之间最短路径的权重值
as delta, u, v. And my goal is to find delta.
u，v。作为三角洲，我的目标是找到三角洲。
It's also to find the path.
这也是寻找路径。
It doesn't help you very much if you
如果您没有太大帮助
know that there's a way of getting from here to Lexington
知道有一种从这里到列克星敦的方式
within 14 miles if you don't know what that path is, right.
如果您不知道那条路在14英里之内，那就对了。
So that's one aspect of it, which
这是它的一方面，
is you want to get the weight.
你想减肥吗？
But you want to get the path as well.
但是，您也想获得一条路。
And these algorithms will do that for you.
这些算法将为您做到这一点。
And in particular, what we want is
特别是我们想要的是
delta u, v to be the minimum over all the paths W p,
在所有路径W p上，delta u，v为最小值，
such that p is in fact the path from u to v.
这样p实际上就是从u到v的路径。
And this is the case where if there exists any such path,
在这种情况下，如果存在任何此类路径，
and the last thing is you want this to be infinity,
最后一件事是你希望这个无限
the weight to be infinity otherwise.
否则权重将为无穷大。
So if you're only talking about roads going from here to Tokyo,
因此，如果您只是在谈论从这里到东京的道路，
should have length infinity.
应该具有无限长。
A little matter of the Pacific Ocean in between.
两者之间有一点太平洋问题。
So that's the set up in terms of the numbers
这就是数字设置
that we want to see.
我们想要看到的。
If you're starting from a particular point,
如果您是从某个特定的角度出发，
you can think of the shortest path length from your source
您可以想到来源中最短的路径长度
as being a 0.
为0。
Initially, everything is infinity
最初，一切都是无限的
because you haven't found any paths yet.
因为您还没有找到任何路径。
And what you're going to do is try and reduce these infinities
而您要做的就是尝试减少这些无穷大
down for all of the vertices that
向下的所有顶点
are reachable from the source vertex.
可以从源顶点到达。
And it's quite possible that you may be given a graph where
而且很可能会给你一张图，其中
a particular vertices, or in your set
特定的顶点，或在您的集合中
V, that can't be reached from the particular source
V，无法从特定来源获得
that you started with.
是您开始的。
And for those vertices, you're going to have your delta u,
对于那些顶点，您将拥有自己的增量，
v. If v is unreachable from you, it will stay at infinity.
v。如果v无法到达您，它将保持无限。
So let's look at an example.
因此，让我们看一个例子。
Let's take-- it's going to be an iterative process here
让我们来-这将是一个迭代过程
of finding the shortest paths.
寻找最短路径。
And so let's take an example that
因此，让我们举一个例子
corresponds to a fairly complex graph,
对应一个相当复杂的图，
or at least a nontrivial one, where that's my source vertex.
或至少是一个平凡的，这就是我的原始顶点。
And I've labeled these other vertices A through F.
我将这些其他顶点标记为A到F。
And I have a bunch of edges.
而且我有很多优势。
5.
5，
I got one more here.
我又来了一个。
So that's what's given to me.
这就是给我的。
And I want to find delta S plugged in for u.
我想找到为您插入的deltaS。
And A, B, D, et cetera plugged in for V for this graph.
此图的A，B，D等插入了V。
And let's just do this manually if you will.
如果需要的话，让我们手动进行此操作。
And just trying to do some kind of breadth first search.
而只是尝试进行某种广度优先搜索。
And we do know breadth first search.
而且我们知道广度优先搜索。
We know depth first search.
我们知道深度优先搜索。
You can imagine trying to use those notions to try and find
您可以想象尝试使用这些概念来尝试找到
the shortest paths here.
最短的路径在这里。
So now we have to prove afterwards
所以现在我们必须证明
when we are done that these are, in fact, the shortest paths.
当我们完成这些操作时，实际上是最短的路径。
And that's the hard part of it.
这就是困难的部分。
But we can certainly try and fill in some numbers associated
但是我们当然可以尝试填写一些相关的数字
with paths that we do know about.
使用我们确实知道的路径。
So I'm going to say that the numbers that
所以我要说的是
are inside each of these vertices-- d of u
在每个这些顶点内-的d
is the current weight.
是当前重量。
And so initially, I'm going to start with D of S being 0,
因此，首先，我将以S的D为0开始，
because that's a source.
因为那是来源
And all of these other ones are going
所有其他这些都在
to have-- I'm not going to write this down--
有-我不会写下来-
but they're going to have infinity for their D of Vs.
但他们的D值将无穷大。
So D of A is infinity.
所以A的D是无穷大。
Do of B is infinity, et cetera.
B的Do是无穷大，等等。
And what I want to do is decrease this D number
我想做的就是减少这个D数
to the point where I'm confident that all of the D numbers
到我有信心所有D数字
that are inside these vertices, these are the current weights,
这些顶点内部的这些是当前的权重，
or end up being the delta numbers.
或最终成为增量数。
So my algorithm is done when my d numbers shrink down.
因此，当我的d数减少时，我的算法就完成了。
And I got the delta values, the correct delta values.
我得到了增量值，正确的增量值。
But if I wanted to do this, sort of a seat of the pants
但是如果我想这样做，可以坐在裤子上
approach, just go off and try and iteratively
方法，只是去尝试并迭代
reduce these numbers, you say, well, this one was infinity.
减少这些数字，你说，嗯，这是无穷大。
But clearly, if I start from S and I follow the edges in S,
但是很明显，如果我从S开始并且跟随S的边缘，
I'm going to be able to mark this as a one.
我将能够将此标记为一个。
And similarly here, I'm going to be able to mark this as a 2.
同样在这里，我将能够将此标记为2。
Now, I could arbitrarily pick this one
现在，我可以任意选择
here and this A vertex, and then start
在这里和这个A顶点，然后开始
looking at the edges that emanate from the A vertex.
观察从A顶点发出的边缘。
And I could go off and mark this as 6, for example.
例如，我可以将其标记为6。
And if I start from here, I'd mark this as 3.
如果我从这里开始，我将其标记为3。
Now, is it in fact true that 6 equals
现在，真的等于6
delta S comma C equals 6?
delta S逗号C等于6？
No.
没有。
What is in fact-- is there a better way of getting to C?
实际上是什么？有没有更好的方法去C？
And what is the weight of that?
重量是多少？
What vertex do I have to go through?
我必须经历什么顶点？
I mean, one way is to go from S to B to D to C, right?
我的意思是，一种方法是从S到B再到D再到C，对不对？
And that would give me 5 right?
那会给我5对吗？
So that's 5.
那就是5。
Can I do better than 5?
我可以做得比5好吗？
Not in this graph.
不在此图中。
OK
好
So it's not the case that the shortest length path gave you
所以不是最短的路径给你
the smallest weight.
最小的重量。
I mean, that was one example of that.
我的意思是，这就是一个例子。
And I can go on an and bore you with filling
我可以继续给您带来无聊
in all of these numbers.
在所有这些数字中。
But you can do that on your own.
但是您可以自己完成。
And it's really not particularly edifying to do that.
这样做确实没有特别的启发意义。
But you get a sense of what you need
但是您会了解所需的东西
to be able to do in order to converge on the delta.
为了能够在三角洲上汇合而做。
And it might take some doing.
这可能需要一些时间。
Because you have to somehow enumerate in an implicit way--
因为您必须以某种方式隐式枚举-
you can't do it in an explicit way,
你不能以明确的方式做到这一点，
because then there'd be an exponential number of paths.
因为那样的话，路径的数量将成倍增长。
But you'd have to implicitly enumerate
但是您必须隐式枚举
all the different ways that you can possibly get to a vertex
可能到达顶点的所有不同方式
and discover the shortest path through that process,
并找到通过该过程的最短路径，
all right.
好吧。
And so we have to be able to do that in these shortest path
因此，我们必须能够在最短的路径上做到这一点
algorithms.
算法。
And this is a simple graph that has positive weights,
这是一个具有正权重的简单图形，
non-negative weights with edges.
带边的非负权重。
It gets more complicated when you have negative weights.
如果负权重会变得更加复杂。
But before I get to that, there's one other thing
但是在我明白之前，还有另一件事
that I want to talk about here with respect
我想在这里谈论一下
to discovering the actual path.
发现实际路径。
So what we did here was we had delta u,
所以我们在这里所做的就是我们有了delta u，
v that corresponded to the weight of the shortest path.
v对应于最短路径的权重。
But if you want the path itself, we
但是，如果您想要路径本身，我们
need to have a way of finding the sequence of vertices that
需要有一种方法来找到顶点的序列
corresponds to the minimum weight path.
对应于最小重量路径。
And in particular, we're going to have
特别是，我们将拥有
to define what we call the predecessor relationship.
定义我们所谓的前身关系。
And so what I have is d of V is the value
所以我的V的d是值
inside the circle, which is the current weight.
在圆圈内，即当前的重量。
And as d is something you're very interested in,
由于d是您非常感兴趣的事物，
eventually you want it to go to delta.
最终，您希望它进入增量。
The other thing that you're very interested in--
您非常感兴趣的另一件事-
and this is really a fairly straightforward data structure
这确实是一个相当简单的数据结构
corresponding to just the d number and this predecessor
仅对应于d号和此前任
number.
数。
And pi of V is the predecessor vertex on the best path to V.
V的pi是通向V的最佳路径的前任顶点。
And you said, pi of S equals NIL.
您说过，S的pi等于NIL。
And then you can think of this as this is eventually
然后您可以考虑一下，因为这最终
what we want, and this gets modified as well.
我们想要的东西，它也会被修改。
So right now, when you're working and trying
所以现在，当您工作和尝试时
to find the path, you have some particular path
找到路径，您有一些特定的路径
that happens to be the current best path.
恰好是当前的最佳途径。
And that's a sequence of vertices
那是一系列的顶点
that you can get by following the predecessors.
您可以通过跟随前辈获得。
So once you're at a particular vertex E, you say all right,
因此，一旦到达特定的顶点E，就可以说了，
right now I can look at pi of E. And if that points me to C,
现在，我可以查看E的pi。如果这将我指向C，
then that's good.
那很好。
I'm going to look at pi of C. And that might point me
我要看C的pi。这可能会指出我
to A, and so on and so forth.
到A，依此类推。
In this particular instance, pi of E
在此特定情况下，E的pi
is going to, when you're finally done, is going to point to A.
当您最终完成操作时，将指向A。
And pi of A is going to point to S, all right, because that's
A的pi将指向S，好的，因为那是
the path that is the best path is this one.
最好的路径就是这一条。
Like so and like that.
像这样。
And so those are the two data structures
这就是两个数据结构
you need to keep in mind that you need to iterate on,
您需要记住，您需要进行迭代，
this predecessor relationship and the current distance.
这个先前的关系和当前距离。
And then this ends up being delta.
然后这最终成为增量。
You're done.
你完成了。
And at that point, your predecessor relationship
到那时，您的前任关系
is correct.
是正确的。
So that's the set up.
这就是设置。
The last complication I want to talk about here
我想在这里谈论的最后一个并发症
is negative weights.
是负重量。
And it's, I think, appropriate to talk about it when
我认为应该在什么时候谈论它
we have Bellman-Ford up here.
我们在这里有贝尔曼福特。
Which is really the general algorithm.
这实际上是通用算法。
So let's talk about-- so the first question is why.
因此，让我们谈谈-所以第一个问题是为什么。
Why do these things exist, other than making
为什么这些东西存在，除了使
our lives more difficult?
我们的生活更艰难？
So give me an example.
所以举个例子。
What is the motivation for a graph with negative weights?
负权图的动机是什么？
I mean, I really would like to know.
我的意思是，我真的很想知道。
The best motivation is definitely worth recursion.
最好的动机绝对值得递归。
Then I can use it next time.
那我下次可以用
Yeah, go ahead.
是的，继续。
AUDIENCE: I'm just thinking like if your goal,
听众：我只是在想，如果你的目标，
if your goal [INAUDIBLE].
如果您的目标是[听不清]。
And some of them cost too much.
其中一些成本太高。
Some of them get you money, and you
他们中有些人赚钱，而你
want to know what-- you're trying to find [INAUDIBLE].
想知道是什么-您正在尝试找到[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
Yeah, I mean, I think that's a good motivation.
是的，我的意思是，我认为这是一个很好的动机。
I think driving, when you think about distances
当您考虑距离时，我认为驾驶
and so on, there's no notion of a negative distance,
依此类推，没有负距离的概念，
at least physically.
至少在身体上。
But you can imagine that you could have a case where you're
但您可以想象，您可能会遇到
getting paid to drive or something,
得到开车或其他东西的报酬，
or it costs you to drive, and that would be one.
否则开车就要花钱，那将是一个。
Yeah, go ahead.
是的，继续。
AUDIENCE: It sounds like Monopoly.
听众：听起来像是垄断。
So the vertices are supposed to be [INAUDIBLE].
因此，顶点应该是[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Oh, if you land on something,
教授：哦，如果你降落在某个地方，
you have to pay rent.
你得付房租
Or sometimes you land on something
有时你落在某物上
and you actually get money.
你实际上就赚钱了
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Takes you forward, backwards, right.
教授：带您前进，后退，正确。
Yeah go ahead.
是的，继续吧。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So that is such an interesting notion.
教授：这是一个很有趣的概念。
Sometimes you may want to go.
有时您可能想去。
And maybe in this case, you're saying
也许在这种情况下，你是说
it's better to take your distance metric
最好采用距离度量
and go further away in order to get the best way of getting
并走得更远以获得最佳的获取方式
there, or something like that.
在那里，或者类似的东西。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
Sure.
当然。
That'd be good.
那就好
Right.
对。
Victor, you had your hand up.
维克多，你举起了手。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
I'm going to give [INAUDIBLE] on the highway,
我要在高速公路上给[听不清]，
you can't [INAUDIBLE] distances [INAUDIBLE] negative.
您不能[音频不清晰]的距离[音频不清晰]为负。
Well, if a government uses [INAUDIBLE] police
好吧，如果政府使用[听不清]警察
to regulate traffic, then you might have a negative distance.
来调节流量，那么您可能会有一个负距离。
Because obviously, you could go a certain way
因为很明显，您可以采取某种方式
minus the [INAUDIBLE].
减去[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
Yeah, that's a good example.
是的，这是一个很好的例子。
One of the things that we have to think about
我们必须考虑的事情之一
is-- and this is something that might come up,
是-这可能会出现，
by the way, in a problem set or a quiz-- which is, is there
顺便说一句，在问题集中或测验中
a way of shifting these weights to make them all positive?
一种转移这些权重以使其全部为正的方法？
So the examples we've talked about, not clear to me
所以我们刚才讲的例子对我来说还不清楚
that in the particular settings that we talked about
在我们讨论的特定设置中
that you can somehow create the base
您可以以某种方式创建基础
case to be 0 rather than being negative.
情况是0而不是负数。
So it may not be possible in a particular scenario.
因此，在特定情况下可能是不可能的。
But if you can do that-- and the reason
但是，如果可以做到的话-原因
I bring this up is if you can do that, suddenly
我想说的是，如果你能做到，突然
instead of using an order V, E algorithm,
而不是使用V，E阶算法，
if you can prove correctness of the final solution
如果您可以证明最终解决方案的正确性
is exactly what you'd have gotten for the initial problem
这正是您最初遇到的问题
certification, you've gone from an order V, E algorithm
认证，您已经脱离了V，E阶算法
to an order V log V algorithm.
到V阶V log V算法。
So that's a wonderful thing to do.
所以这是一件很棒的事情。
So keep that in mind.
所以记住这一点。
Try and get rid of negative weight edges if you can
如果可以，请尝试消除负的负边缘
without changing the problem certification.
无需更改问题证明。
I saw a hand back there.
我看到那里有一只手。
AUDIENCE: Oh, no.
听众：哦，不。
I thought you were just asking the question,
我以为你只是在问一个问题，
if we could do that?
如果可以的话？
So I was just gettin ready to answer.
所以我只是准备回答。
PROFESSOR: OK, yeah, so that's something to keep in mind.
教授：是的，所以要记住这一点。
One example that I think has come up here, which came up,
我认为这里出现了一个例子，
I think, the last time I lectured
我想，我上一次讲课
was imagine that you're driving and there
想象你在开车
are all these advertisements.
这些都是广告。
And you get paid to drive on a freeway.
而且您会获得在高速公路上开车的报酬。
So the reverse toll.
因此，反向收费。
I mean, it's a reverse toll, because you get to go there
我的意思是，这是反向收费，因为您可以去那里
and you have to see all these ads.
而且您必须看到所有这些广告。
And then I guess you drive pretty fast through those ads.
然后，我想您可以通过这些广告快速地进行搜索。
But you have to go through.
但是你必须经历。
And so you get paid to go through those particular roads.
这样一来，您就可以获得报酬，可以穿越那些特定的道路。
And then what about social networks?
然后社交网络呢？
I mean, there's liking people and disliking people.
我的意思是，有喜欢的人和讨厌的人。
I mean, that sounds pretty-- that's negative and positive.
我的意思是，这听起来很不错-既消极又积极。
One could imagine that social networks would
可以想象，社交网络会
have positive weights and negative weights.
具有正权重和负权重。
I'm surprised one of you-- I mean,
我很惊讶你们中的一个-我的意思是，
I don't have an account on Facebook.
我在Facebook上没有帐户。
But presumably, you guys do.
但是大概，你们会的。
So think of what's the-- yeah, that's right.
因此，请考虑-是的，没错。
Well, I'm not sure how this works.
好吧，我不确定这是如何工作的。
But you guys figure it out.
但是你们弄清楚了。
So why?
所以为什么？
Reverse tolls, social networks.
反向收费，社交网络。
Lots of things.
很多事情。
Even if you're not convinced by the motivation,
即使您不相信这种动机，
I will spend a whole lecture talking about Bellman-Ford.
我将在整个演讲中谈论贝尔曼福特。
So that's just so that's clear.
这样就很清楚了。
So the issue with the negative weight cycles
所以负循环的问题
is something that is worth spending a minute on.
值得花一分钟的时间。
And I talked about the fact that you
我谈到了你
had an exponential number of paths.
路径的数量成倍增加。
And that causes a bit of a problem,
这会引起一些问题，
even in the case where you have positive weights.
即使您的体重是正数。
And I will revisit that example.
我将重温该示例。
But here's an even worse problem that
但这是一个更严重的问题
corresponds to negative cycles.
对应于负周期。
So eventually, you want to terminate.
所以最终，您想终止。
The faster you terminate, and if you
您终止的速度越快，如果您
can talk about asymptotic complexity,
可以谈论渐近复杂性，
obviously that means that you've terminated
显然，这意味着您已经终止了
within a worst case bound of time.
在最坏的时间范围内。
And if that's exponential, that's bad.
如果那是指数的，那就不好了。
You'd want it to be small.
您希望它很小。
But what if you didn't even terminate?
但是，如果您甚至没有终止怎么办？
So suppose you have something like this
所以假设你有这样的事情
where you have a graph that has negative weights on some
您的图上有些负权重
of the edges.
的边缘。
But others are positive.
但是其他人是积极的。
So this one has a minus 6.
所以这个数字是负6
I think I got those right.
我想我没错。
So 2 for minus 6 over here, 3, 2, 1, and minus 2.
所以2代表这里的负6、3、2、1和负2。
So one thing that you notice from this graph
您从这张图中注意到的一件事
is that you got this annoying cycle here.
是您在这里遇到了这个烦人的周期。
That's a negative weight cycle.
那是负的体重循环。
And that's why I've picked this particular example.
这就是为什么我选择了这个特定示例。
Minus 6 plus 2 is minus 4.
负6加2为负4。
Minus 4 plus 3 is minus 1.
负4加3为负1。
So if you had something where you can't depend on the fact
因此，如果您有某些地方无法依靠事实
that the D's are going to keep reducing.
D将继续减少。
And that eventually, they'll stop reducing.
最终，它们将停止减少。
Well, that's true.
好吧，那是真的。
Eventually, they'll stop reducing.
最终，它们将停止减少。
Because they're lower bounded by 0
因为它们的下界是0
when you have positive weight edges or non-negative weight
当您有正负重边缘或非负重时
edges.
边缘。
But if you have a graph with a negative cycle-- and I mean,
但是，如果您有一个周期为负的图形-我是说，
this is a recipe for an infinite loop, right--
这是无限循环的秘诀，对吧-
in your program, potentially a bug.
在您的程序中，可能是一个错误。
But maybe not even a bug, not a bug in implementation,
但也许不是错误，也不是实施中的错误，
but a bug in the algorithm.
而是算法中的错误。
Because this determination condition isn't set properly.
因为此确定条件设置不正确。
So you can imagine that you would
所以你可以想象你会
get to B and the first time-- whoops,
第一次去B-哎呀，
I'm missing a weight here.
我在这里没有重量。
So you get to B. And you say, well, I'm done.
所以您到了B。您说，好，我完成了。
Delta of SB is 4.
SB的Delta为4。
But that's not true.
但这不是事实。
Because you could get to B. And then you could get
因为你可以到达B。然后你可以到达
back to B with the weight of 3.
以3的重量回到B
And then you could do it again with the weight of 2,
然后您可以用2的权重再做一次
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
So that's a problem.
所以这是一个问题。
So what would you like an algorithm to do?
那么，您想让算法做什么？
What would you like the Bellman-Ford to do here?
您想要贝尔曼福特在这里做什么？
It's not the case that all of the delta values,
并非所有的差值都可以
that is the shortest path values,
那是最短的路径值
are undefined for this graph.
此图未定义。
Some of them are well defined.
其中一些定义明确。
This one, you can't ever get back to it.
这个，您再也回不来了。
So clearly, delta S, S is 0.
很明显，增量S，S为0。
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
What about this one?
这个如何？
It's 2, right.
是2，对
Delta S, A is 2.
Delta S，A为2。
And everybody buys that, because there's just no way.
每个人都买那个，因为那是没有办法的。
You can't, you don't touch a negative weight cycle.
您不能，您不会碰负的体重循环。
You, in fact, don't touch a negative weight edge.
实际上，您不要碰负重边缘。
But more importantly, you don't touch a negative weight cycle
但更重要的是，您不会碰到负的体重循环
in order to get to A. And there's
为了到达A。
no way of touching that.
无法触及。
On the other hand, anything that's in here
另一方面，这里的任何东西
you could run many times.
您可以运行很多次。
And you could end up with whatever weight you wanted.
您最终可能会承受所需的重量。
There'd be a minus infinity weight.
负无穷大。
So what you want an algorithm that
所以你想要一个算法
handles in particular negative cycles,
处理特别不利的周期，
which are the hard part here.
这是这里的难点。
Negative weights aren't the hard part
负权重并非难事
if you can't run through these edges more than once.
如果您不能多次穿越这些边缘。
It's actually the negative cycles that are hard.
实际上，负面循环很难。
And the negative cycles are going
负面循环正在发生
to make shortest path lengths indeterminate, but not
使最短路径长度不确定，但不是
necessarily for every node in the graph,
对于图中的每个节点，
like this example shows.
如本例所示。
So what you want your Bellman-Ford algorithm to do,
因此，您希望您的Bellman-Ford算法能够做到，
or your shortest path algorithm that
或您的最短路径算法
handles negative cycles to do, is
处理负循环要做的是
to finish in reasonable amounts of time.
在合理的时间内完成。
Order V, E will take and give you
订单V，E将接送您
the delta numbers for all of the vertices
所有顶点的增量数
that actually have finite numbers
实际上有有限的数
and then mark all of these other vertices
然后标记所有其他这些顶点
as being indeterminate, or essentially minus infinity.
是不确定的，或者本质上是无穷大。
OK
好
So that's your termination condition.
这就是您的终止条件。
It's different from the termination condition
与终止条件不同
if you simply had non-negative edge weights.
如果您只是具有非负边缘权重。
All right.
好吧。
So remember, it's cycles that cause a problem, not just
所以请记住，导致问题的是周期，而不仅仅是
the edges.
边缘。
And you have to do something about the cycles.
而且您必须对周期进行一些处理。
But they may not affect the entire part of the computation.
但是它们可能不会影响整个计算过程。
So if you don't know that you have a cycle or not,
因此，如果您不知道自己是否有周期，
then you end up with having to use Bellman-Ford.
然后您最终不得不使用Bellman-Ford。
And so that also tells you something which is interesting,
这样也可以告诉您一些有趣的事情，
which is Bellman-Ford has to detect negative cycles.
Bellman-Ford必须检测到负周期。
If Bellman-Ford couldn't detect negative cycles,
如果Bellman-Ford无法检测到负周期，
then how could it possibly be a correct algorithm
那怎么可能是正确的算法
for the arbitrary case?
对于任意情况？
So Dijkstra doesn't have to do that.
因此，Dijkstra不必这样做。
And that's why Dijkstra is simpler.
这就是Dijkstra更简单的原因。
All right.
好吧。
So let me talk about the general structure of shortest path
所以让我说说最短路径的一般结构
algorithms.
算法。
And the 2 important notions that I want to talk about here
我想在这里谈论的两个重要概念
are the notion of relaxation, which we sort of did already
是放松的概念，我们已经做了放松
when we ran through this example.
当我们通过这个例子。
But I need to formalize that.
但是我需要对此进行形式化。
And then we'll go back and revisit this exponential graph
然后，我们将返回并重新查看该指数图
example.
例。
So the general structural of shortest path algorithms
所以最短路径算法的一般结构
are as follows.
如下面所述。
We're going to initialize for all u belonging to the vertex
我们将初始化所有属于顶点的u
set, we set d v to be infinity.
设置，我们将dv设置为无穷大。
And we set the predecessor to be NIL.
我们将前身设置为NIL。
And then we'll set d of S to be 0.
然后将S的d设置为0。
We're talking about a single source, here.
我们在这里谈论的是单一来源。
We'll set that to be 0.
我们将其设置为0。
And what we're going to do is essentially repeat.
我们要做的基本上是重复。
Select some edge u comma v. And I'm not specifying how.
选择一些用逗号隔开的边缘。我没有指定具体方法。
This is going to result in a different algorithm
这将导致不同的算法
depending on the specifics of how.
取决于具体的方式。
But the important notion is that we're going to relax edge u,
但是重要的一点是，我们将放松您的优势，
v. And what the notion of relaxation is
v。放松的概念是什么
is that you're going to look at it.
是你要去看它。
And you'll say, well, if d of v is greater than d of u
你会说，好吧，如果v的d大于u的d
plus w u, v, then I've discovered a better
再加上吴，五，然后我发现了一个更好的
way of getting to v then I currently know.
到v的方式，我目前知道。
So d of v would currently be infinity,
所以v的d当前为无穷大，
which means I haven't found a way of getting to v yet.
这意味着我还没有找到上v的方法。
But I know that d of u, for example, is a finite number.
但是我知道u的d是一个有限数。
And I do know that this edge exists from u to v, which
而且我知道从u到v都存在该边，
means that I can update the value of d of v.
表示我可以更新v的d值。
And that's what we call relaxation of the edge u, v.
这就是所谓的边u，v的松弛。
And so what you do here is if the if is true,
因此，如果if为真，那么您在这里要做的是，
then you set d, v to be d, u plus w u, v.
然后将d，v设置为d，u加wu，v。
And you'll also update the predecessor relationship,
而且您还将更新先前的关系，
because the current best predecessor for v
因为目前v最好的前身
is going to be u.
将会是你。
So that's the notion of relaxation.
这就是放松的概念。
And I kind of ran out of room here.
我有点在这里没房间了。
But you keep doing this.
但是你继续这样做。
This repeat.
重复一遍。
So what is the repeat?
那么重复的是什么呢？
Well, the repeat is until all edges
好吧，重复直到所有边缘
have d of v less than or equal to d of u plus w u, v.
v的d小于或等于u加wu的d，v。
And the assumption here is that you have no negative cycles.
并且这里的假设是您没有负周期。
We need a different structure.
我们需要一个不同的结构。
The notion of relaxation is still going to be relevant.
放松的概念仍然有意义。
But don't think of this structure
但是不要认为这种结构
as being the structure that Bellman-Ford uses,
作为Bellman-Ford使用的结构，
or algorithms that can handle negative cycles use.
或可以处理负面循环的算法。
So hopefully, you got the notion of relaxation,
因此，希望您有了放松的想法，
which is from a pictorial standpoint,
从绘画的角度来看，
it's simply something that we did
这只是我们所做的
when we looked at updating the value of 6 to 5, for example.
例如，当我们查看将值更新为6时。
So we said through this process, if I
所以我们说通过这个过程，如果我
relax this particular edge and d was already set up--
放宽这个特定的边缘，并且d已经设置好-
let's say d, the vertex here had 3.
假设d，此处的顶点为3。
And this was originally 6.
这原来是6。
And I look at it and I say, D of C is 6.
我看着它说，C的D是6
On other hand, 6 is greater than d
另一方面，6大于d
of the vertex D, which happens to be 3 plus 2.
顶点D的3，恰好是3加2。
And since 5 is less than 6, I can relax this edge
由于5小于6，所以我可以放宽这个优势
and update the value of 6 to 5.
并将值更新为6。
And then I update the predecessor relationship
然后我更新前任关系
to have a pi of C to be D. That's
具有C的pi为D。
the notion of relaxation.
放松的概念。
Fundamental notion.
基本概念。
Going to use it in every algorithm that we talk about.
将在我们讨论的每种算法中使用它。
When do you stop?
你什么时候停下来
Well, when you don't have negative cycles,
好吧，当你没有负面循环时，
there's a fairly clean termination condition,
有一个相当干净的终止条件，
which says that you can't relax any of the edges any more.
这表示您无法再放松任何边缘。
OK You get to the point where you
好吧，你到了你的地步
have values that are associated with each
具有与每个关联的值
of these vertices inside.
里面的这些顶点。
And it doesn't matter what edge you pick,
无论您选择什么优势，
you can't improve them.
你无法改善他们。
So this termination condition, it
所以这个终止条件
could involve an order E check.
可能涉及订单E支票。
So we're not talking complexity here
所以我们这里不谈论复杂性
yet in terms of being efficient.
但就效率而言。
But you can imagine when I say until all edges cannot be
但是你可以想象，当我说直到所有边缘都无法
relaxed, that you'd have to look at all the edges.
放松一下，那你就得看所有的边缘。
And if any one of them can be relaxed,
如果其中任何一个可以放松，
it's possible that another one can now be relaxed.
现在有可能另一个人可以放松。
So you've got to keep going until you get to the point
因此，您必须继续前进，直到达到重点为止
where none of the edges can be relaxed.
边缘无法放松的地方。
So this is a brute force algorithm.
因此，这是一种蛮力算法。
And it'll work.
而且会起作用。
It'll just be slow.
只会很慢。
It'll work for known negative cycles.
它适用于已知的负周期。
And if you just kind of randomly select these edges
如果您只是随机选择这些边缘
and just keep going, I'll give you
继续前进，我给你
an example where it works pretty badly in a minute.
一个例子，它在一分钟内效果很差。
But this is an algorithm.
但这是一种算法。
So I guess I lied when I said we weren't
所以我想我说我们不是在撒谎
going to give you an algorithm.
给你一个算法
It is an algorithm.
这是一种算法。
It's just an algorithm that you never want to implement.
这只是您永远不想实现的算法。
You do want to implement the relaxation condition.
您确实要实现松弛条件。
But not this random way of selecting edges and having
但不是这种随机选择边的方式
this termination condition that, in of itself,
这种终止条件本身就是
is an order E check.
是订单E支票。
And one of the reasons why you don't
而你不这样做的原因之一
want to implement this algorithm is coming up shortly
要实现此算法不久
in our exponential graph example.
在我们的指数图示例中。
But let me make sure that people aren't bored.
但是让我确保人们不会感到无聊。
Any questions about the general structure,
有关总体结构的任何疑问，
relaxation, anything?
放松，什么？
Are we good?
好吗
OK.
好。
So you guys, I walk away from lecture thinking
你们，我放弃了演讲的思考
I've given this spectacular lecture and everybody
我给了这场壮观的演讲，大家
understands.
了解。
And then Victor tells me when he shows up
然后维克多告诉我他何时出现
in section in the morning, he says
在早上的部分中，他说
did people understand graphs?
人们了解图表吗？
And everyone says no.
每个人都说不。
Or did people understand x?
还是人们了解x？
And people say no.
人们说不。
So at least tomorrow, tell Victor that you understood.
所以至少到明天，告诉Victor你明白了。
Whether you did or not.
不管你做与否。
So then I feel better.
所以我感觉好多了。
AUDIENCE: That's going to make my life real easy.
听众：这将使我的生活变得轻松。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, right.
教授：是的，对。
So good.
这么好。
Well, you probably like hearing stuff from Victor
好吧，您可能喜欢听Victor讲的东西
better than me anyway.
反正比我更好。
That's the secret here, right?
这就是这里的秘密吧？
All right, so one of the reasons why
好吧，所以原因之一
you don't want to implement this algorithm
你不想实现这个算法
is precisely this example that I put up.
正是我提出的这个例子。
And this is a really neat example that I like a lot,
这是我非常喜欢的一个很好的例子，
because it points out two different things.
因为它指出了两个不同的东西。
It points out that exponential number
指出那个指数数
of paths, an exponential number of paths in a graph,
路径数，图中的指数路径数，
could cause a problem with this algorithm.
可能会导致此算法出现问题。
The other thing that it points out
它指出的另一件事
is that we got issues with the weights of edges.
是我们在边缘权重方面遇到了问题。
One of the nice observations one of you made earlier on
你们中的一个不错的观察之一
is that we had these neat algorithms that did not
是我们有这些整洁的算法
depend on the dynamic range of the weights.
取决于权重的动态范围。
So let's just say that I in fact had
所以让我们说我实际上有
an exponential range for the weights.
权重的指数范围。
I know 4 isn't exponential, but at some level,
我知道4不是指数的，但在某种程度上，
you could imagine that it's exponentially
您可以想象它成指数增长
related to 1 or 2.
与1或2有关。
And the point here is that if I created
关键是，如果我创建了
a graph that looked like this, where I have V4, V5, V6, V7,
像这样的图，其中有V4，V5，V6，V7，
V8, and it had this structure, then
V8，它具有这种结构，然后
I'm going to end up having something
我最终要吃点东西
like 2 raised to n over 2 weight if I
如果我将2提升到2的重量
have n vertices in this graph.
此图中有n个顶点。
Or at least the dynamic range of these weights
或至少这些权重的动态范围
is going to be 2 raised to n divided by 2.
将2提高到n除以2。
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
So think of this graph as being a fragment of this large graph,
因此，将此图视为该大图的一部分，
which where n could be 100 and the weights
其中n可以是100和权重
could be 2 raised to 50.
可能是2提高到50。
And 2 raised to 50 isn't a number
2加到50不是数字
that we can't handle on a computer, right?
我们无法在计算机上处​​理，对吗？
It's still less than 64 bits, right?
它仍然少于64位，对吗？
So it's a pretty reasonable example.
因此，这是一个非常合理的示例。
And we talked about multiple precision arithmetic,
我们讨论了多精度算术，
infinite precision arithmetic.
无限精度算术。
So we can handle arbitrary numbers
这样我们就可以处理任意数字
of an arbitrary position.
任意位置。
So there's nothing that's stopping us
所以没有什么可以阻止我们
from putting square root of 2 and all sorts of things.
取2的平方根和各种各样的东西。
We won't do imaginary numbers.
我们不会做虚数。
But you could imagine putting numbers
但是你可以想象把数字
with a high dynamic range as edges in a particular graph
具有高动态范围作为特定图形中的边缘
and expect the Dijkstra, assuming that all of the edges
并期望Dijkstra，假设所有边缘
are non-negative, that Dijkstra should be able to run on it.
是非负的，Dijkstra应该可以在其上运行。
So what happens with this example?
那么这个例子会怎样？
Well, with this example, here's what happens.
好吧，通过此示例，将发生以下情况。
Let's say that I ran this algorithm.
假设我运行了该算法。
And initially, I just followed this chain here.
最初，我只是在这里遵循此链条。
And I get-- this starts with a 0.
我得到-这从0开始。
And this is a 4, because I get there with 4.
这是4，因为我到了4。
This one is 8.
这个是8
And this is 10.
这是10。
And this is 12, 13, 14.
这是12、13、14
And that's the initial pass.
那是初始阶段。
That's the selection.
那就是选择。
What ends up happening is that you could now relax at this--
最终发生的事情是，您现在可以在此放松一下-
you see 14.
你看到14。
And let's say you relax this edge.
假设您放松了这一优势。
You see that 12 and 14, you've turned that into 13.
您看到12和14，将其变为13。
And then when you relax this edge, this turns into 12.
然后，当您放松此边缘时，将变为12。
So you go through that process.
这样您就可以完成该过程。
Now, this one stays 12.
现在，这个停留12。
But now you relax this edge.
但是现在您放松了这一优势。
And so this 12 becomes 10.
因此，这12变成10。
And then when this changes, you need
然后当这种情况改变时，您需要
to-- if you relax this edge first,
要-如果您先放松这一优势，
then this 13 is going to become 11.
那么这13将变成11
It doesn't really matter.
没关系。
This becomes, I guess, 11.
我猜这就是11。
And-- is that right?
而且-是吗？
Yup.
对。
This is 11 and that's 11 as well.
这是11，也就是11。
It might start out being 12 if you
如果您可能开始是12
relax this edge and that edge.
放松这个边缘和那个边缘。
So you might go to 12 to 11, and so on and so forth.
因此，您可能会转到12到11，依此类推。
So for a pathological ordering, I won't belabor the point.
因此，对于病理性排序，我不会感到惊讶。
But you see that you're going 14, 13, 12,
但是您会看到要走14、13、12
11 with a bad ordering that corresponds
11对应的错误顺序
to the selection of the edges.
到边缘的选择。
And so if the overall weight here and overall weight here,
因此，如果此处的总重量和此处的总重量，
when you start out with, is going
当你开始的时候
to be order 2 raised to n over 2.
将订单2的n提升为2。
OK And you could be, in this particular graph,
好，在这个特定的图中，
relaxing edges an exponential number of times
松弛边缘成指数倍的次数
in order to finish.
为了完成。
And so the number of times you relax an edge
因此，您放松边缘的次数
could be of the order of the weights
可能是权重的数量级
that you start out with.
一开始就是
And that makes this algorithm an exponential time algorithm.
这使该算法成为指数时间算法。
So clearly, we have to do better than that
很明显，我们必须做得更好
when it comes to Dijkstra or Bellman-Ford.
谈到Dijkstra或Bellman-Ford。
So how are we going to do better than that?
那么我们将如何做得更好呢？
Yeah, question back there.
是的，再问那里。
AUDIENCE: Is it an issue that we're
观众：这是我们的问题吗
starting at the [INAUDIBLE]?
从[听不清]开始？
PROFESSOR: You're exactly right.
教授：您说得很对。
There's an issue with the ordering that we've chosen.
我们选择的顺序存在问题。
But what you have to show is that for any graph,
但是您要显示的是对于任何图形，
the particular ordering that you choose
您选择的特定顺序
will result in V log V plus E and so on and so forth.
将导致V log V加E等，依此类推。
So you're exactly right.
所以你说的很对。
I mean, it's an issue with the ordering we've chosen.
我的意思是，这与我们选择的订单有关。
This is a pathological ordering.
这是病理排序。
It's just meaning to say that we have
只是说我们有
to be careful about how we select.
要谨慎选择。
If you selected wrong, you've got problems.
如果选择错误，则说明您遇到了问题。
And so the purpose of next week is
所以下周的目的是
going to be how do we select these edges properly.
我们将如何正确选择这些边缘。
And so I leave you with this notion of,
所以我给你留下这样的观念，
very simple notion of, optimal substructure using
非常简单的概念，使用
two very simple terms that you can
您可以使用两个非常简单的术语
prove in literally a line of text.
用一行文字证明。
And the first one says as subpaths of a shortest path
第一个说作为最短路径的子路径
are shortest paths.
是最短的路径。
And all that means is if I had V0, and I went to V1,
这就是说如果我有V0，然后我转到V1，
and I went to V2, and these are paths here.
我去了V2，这些是这里的路径。
So this could be p01, p02, p03.
因此可能是p01，p02，p03。
And so there are many vertices potentially between V0 and V1.
因此，V0和V1之间可能有许多顶点。
And if you tell me that V0 through V3,
如果您告诉我V0至V3，
the concatenation of p01, p02, and, sorry, p03
p01，p02和对不起p03的串联
are a shortest path.
是最短的路径。
If this is an SP, shortest path, then that
如果这是SP，最短路径，则
implies that each of these are shortest paths as well.
意味着这些都是最短的路径。
And that makes sense, because if in fact there
这是有道理的，因为如果实际上
was a better way of getting from V0 to V1
是从V0转到V1的更好方法
that was better than p01, why would you ever put p01 in here?
那比p01好，为什么还要把p01放在这里呢？
You would use that better way.
您将使用更好的方法。
So very simple.
非常简单。
That's what's called the optimum substructure property.
这就是所谓的最佳子结构属性。
And this notion of the triangle inequality
这个三角形不等式的概念
is also related to that.
也与此有关。
And that simply says that if I have something like this,
这只是说，如果我有这样的事情，
that I have V0, V1, and V2, then when
我有V0，V1和V2，那么当
I look at the delta value of V0, V1,
我看一下V0，V1的增量值
and I compare that with the delta values of V0, V2, and V2,
我将其与V0，V2和V2的增量值进行比较，
V1, then this has got to be smaller than or equal to this
V1，则此值必须小于或等于此值
plus that.
再加上。
And that again makes sense.
这又是有道理的。
Because if this plus this was smaller than that,
因为如果加上这个比那个小，
well remember I'm talking about paths here, not edges.
记住，我在这里谈论的是路径，而不是边缘。
And the better way of getting to V1
以及进入V1的更好方法
would be to follow-- go through V2 rather
将会遵循-而是通过V2
than following this path up on top.
而不是遵循这条道路。
Amazingly, these two notions are going
令人惊讶的是，这两个概念正在
to be enough to take this algorithm
足以采用此算法
and turn it into essentially a linear time algorithm.
并将其转化为实质上的线性时间算法。
And we'll do that next time.
我们下次再做。